Guide to the Front Page newspaper records, 1975-2006 and undated RL.00421
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographs (Accession 2023-0086), 1980-2004
  The photographs in this accession are arranged into three groups: Pride Events, Other Events, and People and Organizations.
  - Pride Events, 1980-2004
    Photographs taken of Pride events, primarily NC Pride, including participants, supporters, vendors, and performances. Photographs show a wide range of people, including: lesbian/gay parents and regional PFLAG (Parents, Families, and Friends of Lesbians and Gays) groups; bisexual and transgender people; drag performers; military personnel and veterans; gay men who self-identify as bears, leatherheads, and cowboys; lesbian women who self-identify as dykes; and supportive religious, racial, ethnic, interracial, and intersectional groups and organizations. Also included are pictures of protestors who attended the events, as well as homophobic signs containing harmful language. Pride events held in North Carolina appear first, followed by those in other states, followed by assorted Pride-related events.
    - Gay Pride Day, Fayetteville, 1980 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 1)
    - Gay Pride, Durham, 1986 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 1)
    - NC Pride, Raleigh, 1988 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 1)
    - NC Pride, Raleigh, 1989 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 1)
    - NC Pride, 1991 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 1)
    - NC Pride, Asheville, 1992 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 1)
    - NC Pride, Raleigh, 1993 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 1)
    - NC Pride, Charlotte, 1994 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 1)
    - NC Pride, Durham, 1995 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 1)
    - NC Pride, Durham, 1995 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
    - Down East Pride, 1995 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
    - NC Pride, Winston-Salem, 1996 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
    - Down East Pride, 1996 September (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
    - NC Pride, circa 1996-1998 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
    - NC Pride, Carrboro - Chapel Hill, 1997 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
    - NC Pride, Asheville, circa 1997-1998 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
    - NC Pride, Asheville - Buncombe County, 1998 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
    - NC Pride, Greensboro, 1999 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
      Photographs by William J. Wolfe, Jr.
    - NC Pride, Durham, 2000 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 2)
    - NC Pride, Durham, 2000 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 3)
    - NC Pride, Durham, circa 2000-2001 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 3)
    - NC Pride, Durham, 2001 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 3)
    - NC Pride, Charlotte, 2001; 2 folders (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 3)
    - NC Pride, Charlotte, 2001 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 3)
    - NC Pride, circa 2003-2004 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 3)
    - SC Pride, Columbia, 1991 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 3)
      Photographs by Chris Allbright.
    - SC Pride, Columbia, circa 1992 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 3)
    - SC Pride, Columbia, circa 1995 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 4)
    - SC Pride, Myrtle Beach, 1998 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 4)
    - Gay Pride, New York City, 1996 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 4)
    - Coming Out as a Community, circa 1980s-1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 4)
    - Pride hats and shirts, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 4)
    - Assorted Pride photos, late 1980s - early 2000s; 3 folders (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 4)
    - Separated contact sheets and negatives, late 1980s - early 2000s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 4)
      Separated by donor/creator.
  - Other Events, late 1980s - early 2000s
    Photographs of events including conventions and conferences, marches, protests and campaigns, AIDS advocacy, and other events. There are also photographs taken of homophobic actions and hate crimes, including graffiti, anti-LGBTQ signs, and arson. Photographs of graffiti and anti-LGBTQ signs contain harmful language.
    - ACT-UP, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 4)
    - AIDS memorial quilt, 1988 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 4)
    - AIDS memorial quilt, 1996 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
      Photographs by Mary Woodward.
    - BGLA mural painting, circa 1997 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Boone Area NOW same-sex wedding ceremony, 1997 February (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
      Photographs from a mock same-sex wedding ceremony as part of a National Day of Action to support same-sex marriage. Includes press release.
    - Candlelight vigil, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Creating Change conference, 1993 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
      Held in Durham, NC.
    - Dance event and graffiti/wall painting, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
      Two groups of photos taken from the same camera roll. The first group is of a dance event, and the second group shows homophobic graffiti (some covered up by LGBTQ-friendly painting) on walls by Duke's campus.
    - Human Rights Campaign gala, 1997 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Kiss-in protest, 1988 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
      Kiss-in held outside Senator Jesse Helms' office to protest Helms' views and legislative actions.
    - Lesbian Mothers March, Raleigh, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - March on Washington, 1993 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Maplethorpe Trial, 1990 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - NOW Conference, Greensboro, circa 1995 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Out Charlotte, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Protes at Duke, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Southeastern Bisexual Conference, 1993-1994 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Stonewall 25, New York City, 1994 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Wedding protest at NC state legislature, 1996 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
      Gay and lesbian wedding ceremony held in protest outside the North Carolina state legislative building.
    - World AIDS Day, 1995 December (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Assorted event photos, circa 1980s-1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 5)
    - Assorted event photos, circa 1980s-1990s; 2 folders (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Homophobia and hate crimes: NC State vandalism, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Homophobia and hate crimes: Graffiti and signs, circa 1980s-1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Homophobia and hate crimes: Danny Leonard fire, 1995 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
      Pictures after a fire at Danny Leonard's home in Jacksonville, NC. Leonard, a drag queen also known as Brandy Alexander, owned Friends Lounge, a gay bar in Jacksonville.
    - Homophobia and hate crimes: White Rabbit fire, 1995 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
      Pictures during and after a fire was intentionally set at White Rabbit Books & Things in Charlotte, NC. White Rabbit was a gay and lesbian bookstore.
    - Separated contact sheets and negatives, late 1980s - early 2000s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
      Separated by donor/creator. Includes some negatives of shoes and unidentified homes.
  - People and Organizations, late 1980s - early 2000s
    - Bill Brent, ASA (AIDS Service Agency), 1997 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Mandy Carter, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Captain Coronado, circa 1980s-1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Wilson Cruz, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - MK Cullen, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Justin Elzie, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Wanda Floyd, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Wanda Floyd and Janice Vaughan, circa 1994 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Katherine Forrest, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - David Fredere, circa 1996 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - The Front Page, late 1980s - 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Wain Gaskill, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - John-Paul Griffin and Tory Woodard, 1996 September (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Joyce Hunter, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - David Jones, 1987-1990 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Don King, circa 1980s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Lynn Lavner, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Lesbian Avengers, 1980s-1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Wayne Lindsey, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Derek Livingston, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Megentta, 1997 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 6)
    - Mike Nelson, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
      Includes pictures of Nelson with and serving on the Carrboro Town Council.
    - NC Pride Marching Band, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
      Many pictures are from NC Pride 1994 in Charlotte.
    - Our Own Place, Durham, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
    - Bob Page, 1997 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
      Includes an issue of Victory! Gay & Lesbian business magazine profiling Bob Page as entrepreneur of the year.
    - Abby Rubenfeld, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
    - St. John's Metropolitan Community Church, circa 1995 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
    - Mab Segrest, 1980s-1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
    - Triad Business and Professional Guild (TBPG), circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
    - Ray Warren, 1998 (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
    - Phill Wilson, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
    - Laurie Wolf, 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
    - Perry Dean Young, circa 1990s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
      Negatives.
    - Assorted people and groups, late 1980s - early 2000s; 2 folders (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)
    - Separated contact sheets and negatives, late 1980s - early 2000s (Box Acc. 23/0086: Box 7)